# **ERIC JIANG**

# Software Engineer

Experienced full stack Software Engineer with 8 years of industry experience building cloud-based solutions in all phases of the software development lifecycle. Demonstrated history of productive remote work and adapting to new challenges to achieve business goals. Eager to bring strong work ethic, interpersonal skills and proven proficiency with balancing priorities and excellence for team success.

### **EDUCATION**

2011-09 -2015-06

### **Bachelor of Science: Computer Science**

University of California - San Diego - La Jolla, CA

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### 2022-08 -Current

### Software Engineer, Backend

Aspiration, Marina Del Rey, CA

- Led architecture, design and implementation of cron job to synchronize disparate finance data from Google Drive to PostgreSQL using Go and AWS Lambda-based architecture.
- Worked closely with internal teams, project stakeholders and external vendors to improve bank integration microservices using Twirp and gRPC frameworks, which directly improved user experience and significantly reduced unnecessary business costs.
- Improved Go microservices by taking initiative to create stories for technical debt and bugs, implementing AWS IAM database authentication, adding effective Datadog monitors and disaster recovery runbooks.
- Mentored junior software engineers through pair programming and code reviews.

#### 2021-07 -2022-08

### **Software Engineer Team Lead**

Bentley Systems, Ann Arbor, MI

- Managed remote software development team using agile methodologies.
- Worked closely with management and project stakeholders to discuss application feature design and project progress.
- Collaborated with clients to define solution requirements and collect feedback for products and workflows to analyze digital twin data.

#### 2020-12 -2021-07

## Software Engineer II

Bentley Systems, Ann Arbor, MI

- Spearheaded development of scalable data transformation pipeline for new reporting platform through writing user stories, refining requirements with management and project stakeholders, designing architecture and prototype using Azure, C#, JSON.
- Led design and implementation of key features for infrastructure analytics cloud service using Azure, C#, Angular and React.
- Mentored junior software engineers and interns regularly through code reviews, teaching best practices, providing learning resources, and creating opportunities for them to own projects and tasks.

### 2017-07 -2020-12

## Software Engineer I

Bentley Systems, San Diego, CA

- Led architecture, design and implementation of complex data extraction pipeline to curate infrastructure data from multiple data sources for insights and reporting in web applications and Power BI.
- Developed and evolved REST APIs for infrastructure analytics cloud service using C#, ASP.NET, OData, SQL Server, MongoDB.
- Adjusted application design regularly to align with customer requirements and changes with business direction.

### CONTACT

#### **Address**

Ann Arbor, MI 48103

#### Phone

(408) 781-8359

#### E-mail

jbneric@gmail.com

### **LANGUAGES**

C#

Go

TypeScript

JavaScript

### **SKILLS**

.NET

**Angular** 

Azure

AWS

REST API

RPC

PostgreSQL

SQL Server

NoSQL

Datadog

Azure DevOps

CircleCl

Octopus Deploy

Docker

### 2015-07 -2017-07

# **Associate Software Engineer**

Bentley Systems, Carlsbad, CA

- Spearheaded full stack development to prototype infrastructure analytics web application featured at global Year in Infrastructure conference using C#, ASP.NET, AngularJS, OData, SQL Server, MongoDB.
- Upgraded Infrastructure Asset Management web application by converting significant amount of AngularJS code from JavaScript to TypeScript.

### **HOBBIES**

Live Sound, Music Production, DJ, Powerlifting